A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Asia Programs, Bangladesh, Dacca (Dhaka) Program Staff Files FA504
Rockefeller Archive Center
Ford Foundation records, Asia Programs, Bangladesh, Dacca (Dhaka) Program Staff Files
1972-1998
Rockefeller Archive Center
Ford Foundation
FA504
3.6 Cubic Feet
Conditions Governing Access note
Material is open for scholarly research, with prior archival review.
Material more than ten years old is open for scholarly research.
Select individual files are restricted, as noted. Permission to access these files must be obtained from the Ford Foundation before scholarly access is permitted.
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
Ford Foundation archive was deposited at RAC in 2011. Ford Foundation records, correspondence, reports, program files and officers papers were transferred to, and accessioned by, RAC beginning in 2011. Accessions continue as necessary.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements note
Materials requiring specialized equipment for access (film, audio, video, slides) may be restricted from scholarly research dependent on availability of the applicable equipment. Brittle or damaged items, or materials otherwise in need of preservation care, may be restricted from scholarly research at the discretion of the RAC Head of Archival Services/RAC Head of Reference.
Ford Foundation
- Consultants and Program Files, 1972-1988; I
  - Basic Documents Vol. I (1/2), 1972-1973 (Box 1)
  - Basic Documents Vol. II (2/2), 1972-1996 (Box 1)
  - Geoff Wood, 1973 (Box 1)
  - Leon E. Clark, 1975 (Box 1)
  - Dr. Geoffry D. Wood, 1975-1985 (Box 1)
  - Reports on BARD Consultancy (1/2), 1976-1987 (Box 1)
  - Reports on BARD Consultancy (2/2), 1976-1987 (Box 1)
  - Dr. Mark Pitt, 1976-1980 (Box 1)
  - Robert C. Terry Jr., Nov 15, 1979 (Box 1)
  - Shamim Hamid, [1980] (Box 1)
  - Dr. Nicholas Cohen, 1980-1981 (Box 1)
  - Dr. Geoffrey D. Wood, 1981 (Box 1)
  - Hameeda Hossain, Roushan Jahan and Salama Sobhan, [1982] (Box 1)
  - V.C. Joshi (1/3), 1986-1987 (Box 1)
  - V.C. Joshi (2/3), 1988-1989 (Box 1)
  - V.C. Joshi (3/3), 1989-1995 (Box 1)
  - V. Fauveau and T. Blanchet, May 1988 (Box 1)
  - Kamla Chowdhry, 1988-1989 (Box 2)
  - Martha A. Chen, 1989-1992 (Box 2)
  - Mary Zurbuchen, 1988-1989 (Box 2)
  - William Burch, 1989 (Box 2)
  - Marty Chen, 1989 (Box 2)
  - Asmeen Khan, 1989-1991 (Box 2)
  - Dr. Rounaq Jahan, 1989-1993 (Box 2)
  - Bhasicar Chandavarkar, Nov 22, 1990 (Box 2)
  - Grant Close-Out Memoranda (1/2), 1990-1994 (Box 2)
  - Grant Close-Out Memoranda (2/2), 1995-1998 (Box 2)
  - Najmul Huq, 1992-1995 (Box 2)
  - Anthony Bottrall, 1993 (Box 2)
  - Stephen F Minkin, 1993-1996 (Box 2)
  - Dr. James L Ross, 1994-1995 (Box 2)
  - Alanddin Talukder, 1994-1995 (Box 2)
  - Barbara Whitney, 1994-1995 (Box 2)
  - John W. Thomas, 1994-1995 (Box 2)
  - Marshall Bear and Jennefer Sebstad, 1994-1995 (Box 2)
  - Goutam Ghosh (Computer Disk), 1995-1997 (Box 2)
  - Roushan Jahan, 1993-1995 (Box 2)
  - Stephenie Hollyman, 1996 (Box 2)
  - Dr. A.F. Salahuddin Ahmed, 1996 (Box 2)
  - Peggy Bentley, May 26-Jun 4, 1996 (Box 2)
  - Mark Sidel, 1997 (Box 2)
  - Steve Golub, 1997 (Box 2)
  - Rebecca Walker, 1998 (Box 2)
  - Ian Martin, Feb 28, 1971 (Box 3)
  - Rene Dumont -- Short Notes on Some Villages and Some Problems, Jan 1973 (Box 3)
  - Ralph W. Nicholas -- Some Uses for Social Anthropology in Bangladesh, Jul 1973 (Box 3)
  - Geoffrey D. Wood, 1974 (Box 3)
  - Shirley Lindenbaum -- Social and Economic Status of Women in Bangladesh, Apr 1974 (Box 3)
  - Stephen D. Biggs -- Bangladesh 1975, Jul 1975 (Box 3)
  - Lincoln C. Chen and Rafiqul Huda Chowdhury -- Demographic Changes and Trends of Food Production in Bangladesh, Oct 1975 (Box 3)
  - Miscellaneous Pages, 1975-1990 (Box 3)
  - S. Bruce Schearer -- Fertility Control Technology in Bangladesh, Mar 1976 (Box 3)
  - Gustav F. Papanek -- Strengthening Economics at Dacca University, May 1978 (Box 3)
  - Nancy J. Piet -- Report on PCFP Directorate IEM Division, Jun 1978 (Box 3)
  - Gwatkin, Chowdhury, Pyle -- Health and Nutrition, Bangladesh -- Report to the Ford Foundation Dacca Office, Feb 1, 1980 (Box 3)
  - Stephen D. Biggs -- Review of Rural Poverty and Resources Programs, Apr 1982 (Box 3)
  - Ford Foundation -- Employment and Income Generation, Apr 11-15, 1984 (Box 3)
  - Administrative Background Materials, 1985-1992 (Box 3)
  - Ingrid M. Foik, Oct 1988 (Box 3)
  - Kamla Chowdhry, Feb 1, 1989 (Box 3)
  - Ford Foundation -- Bangladesh Strategy Paper on Women in Development, Oct 13, 1989 (Box 3)
  - Martha A. Chen -- Review of Ford Foundation Women's Programs in Bangladesh, 1990 (Box 3)
  - Enamul Haque -- Overview of Cultural Programmes in Bangladesh, Oct 25, 1991 (Box 3)
  - Dhaka Program Review, May 1992 (Box 3)
  - New York Appointed Staff -- Staff Salaries, Jan 18, 1992 (Box 3)
  - Dhaka Program Review, Mar 1993 (Box 3)
  - Gerard Rixhon -- Report to the Ford Foundation on Support for Human Resource Development, Aug 24, 1993 (Box 3)
  - Marshall A. Bear and Jennefer Sebstad, Mar 1994 (Box 3)
  - Dhaka Program Review, Mar 1995 (Box 3)